<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Allolexicon]]></title>
  <link href="http://allolex.net/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://allolex.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-13T12:20:02+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://allolex.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Damon Davison]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Avoiding bias in software job ads]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/08/11/avoiding-bias/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-11T09:23:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/08/11/avoiding-bias</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many technology businesses are trying to do the right thing by hiring for
diversity. I’ve seen a few examples of job ads from companies who clearly have
so little experience writing job ads, or spend so little time thinking about
what the ad is saying, that they end up offending their target readership.</p>

<p>If you want to attract the right people to your business, you have to be the
kind of business that those people would be proud to work for. Attention to
detail in a job ad, especially in software development, is at least as
important as attention to detail in a CV/resume. It’s important to pay
attention to gender, sexual orientation, and culture in your job description.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Fill your ad full of detail, but keep it neutral.</h3>

<p>You want to have an ad that gives all the important details about your company
and about the available position. To keep this brief, I am going to assume that
you have spent loads of time making sure the work environment is someplace
people want to be. You will want to tell potential hires about the things that
make your company special. Spend some time talking about culture.</p>

<p>Also take the time to write about the kind of person you see in the position
you’d like to fill. What sort of personality would best fit your company? What
kind of approach to problem-solving would be the best fit for your team? If
your team spend time together outside of work, talk about it. Talk about your
product or your clients. The important thing is to provide plenty of detail
about who you are, where you would like to be, and who you think could help you
get there. You may overlook some details, but if you describe your needs
accurately, the right person may just figure out what is missing and fill in
the gaps.</p>

<p>If you are already using a particular software stack, then certainly mention
it, but no one wants to read a list of technologies packaged as a job ad. If
your goal is to solve a problem, then describe your problem and let the experts
figure out whether they are a good match.</p>

<p>The same rule also applies to other aspects of the person you want to hire.
Keep your ad neutral by avoiding bias and the best applicants will select
themselves.</p>

<h3>Avoid gender bias.</h3>

<p>Specifying gender in your job ad is tantamount to specifying race, age, or
religion in your ad, and should be avoided at all costs. There is practically
no way you can write a gender-specific job ad without stereotyping people, so
this practice is best avoided.</p>

<p>Don’t assume things about your target readership. For example, talking about
someone’s girlfriend, boyfriend, husband or wife is a big no-no unless you
include every permutation and give them all equal billing in your ad (or resort
to “spouse” or “partner”). Since that can end up being unreadable, I suggest
you keep the ad copy gender-neutral.</p>

<p>It’s also worth noting that gender is a very fuzzy concept and cannot be
determined by biology. Many of us have put our foot in it at some point in
interviews with people who present (to us) as one gender, but identify as
another. The best rule I can think of for avoiding embarrassment is to look at
how the applicants refer to themselves and use their own terms when talking
about them. Fortunately for hiring managers, people with non-obvious gender
identity are used to people struggling a bit, so any effort tends to be
appreciated.</p>

<h3>Be aware of cultural bias, especially in religious traditions.</h3>

<p>What is normal for you may not be normal for someone else. You can expect
people to adapt to many things to fit in, but religious traditions involve
fundamental beliefs and should be respected. Among other things, these
traditions affect how people dress, what they eat, and their need for personal
time during the day and evenings and weekends.</p>

<p>For example, don’t assume that everyone considers the consumption of alcohol to
be a bonus. The “fridge fully stocked with beer” line may be entirely
appropriate to my culture (and socialisation), but every time I read it, I
cringe inwardly on behalf of the vast numbers of people who find the notion
unwelcoming or offensive.</p>

<h3>Avoid language bias.</h3>

<p>Being too specific about language can appear unwelcoming for people who are not
native to your area. Advertise native proficiency in a language only when it’s
really required by the job: “good” or “very good” is usually enough. If
language is going to be a problem, it will become evident in your communication
during the application process.</p>

<h3>Let&rsquo;s <em>not</em> talk about sex (in professional settings).</h3>

<p>Finally, assuming things about the reader’s sexual orientation should be
avoided at all costs, and any discussion of sexual orientation or preference
should be avoided. I have seen very few job descriptions where sexual
preference was at all relevant, and you’ll probably know if the position you’re
advertising is the exception.</p>

<h1>Let me know what you think!</h1>

<p>I&rsquo;d love to hear about <em>your</em> experiences reading and writing job ads. Do you
think these criteria cover enough cases, or is something missing? Maybe my list
is too long? Please let me know what you think by commenting below.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revisiting Cologne]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/29/revisiting-cologne/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-29T17:54:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/29/revisiting-cologne</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3670/9385121704_350b79a9d1_h.jpg" alt="The Rhine" /></p>

<p>I recently attended <a href="http://2013.railscamp.de">Railscamp Germany 2013</a>, which took place in
Cologne. I met a lot of nice people there and had the opportunity to help out
<a href="https://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=_tyranja_">Anja</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=thatbettina">Bettina</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=sabrna">Sabrina</a> with their cool Rails
Girls Summer of Code project called &ldquo;SpeakerInnen&rdquo;, an app to help get more
women speakers into conferences—a <em>very</em> good idea. Our productivity was ever
so slightly compromised due to the 38C/100F heat that day, but we still got
some useful things sorted out.</p>

<p><a href="http://loopc.am/tyranja/loops/2"><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7365/9392469685_b827817b7c_o.gif" alt="Bettina and I working on Speakerinnen" /></a></p>

<p>But we <em>were</em> actually productive <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=ernestomiguez">Ernesto Miguez</a> and I had
even squashed a tiny SASS bug in the Railscamp &ldquo;sessions&rdquo; app earlier in the
day.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Visiting Cologne served a dual purpose for me, though. I spent many years of my
life in Cologne as a student at the Universität zu Köln and I have a few close
friends from that time who still live there. We see each other only rarely, so
we have to profit from the few opportunities that present themselves, and this was
one such opportunity.</p>

<p>So on Saturday, I left during the hottest part of the hottest day this summer,
and headed back into the cool embrace of my air-conditioned hotel room. On my
way back, I phoned up a friend and made her an offer she couldn&rsquo;t refuse:
air-conditioned comfort in exchange for the pleasure of her company.</p>

<p>This was a reprise of the previous day—with another friend—and together they
ended up being the best parts of my stay in Cologne—the time I got to spend
with my old friends.</p>

<p>And after it cooled down that evening, we even had enough energy to go on a
5km/3mi walk, but only after we took a picture with the Rhein and the Cologne
skyline as a backdrop.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2852/9385107946_e80c3dea41_b.jpg" alt="S and D" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple includes using Markdown]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/21/simple-includes-using-markdown/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-21T11:59:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/21/simple-includes-using-markdown</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been sending out a fair few messages to potential sponsors, applicants,
volunteers and coaches for <a href="http://railsgirls-sfl.org">Rails Girls South Florida</a>. To make this job
easier, I edit all my documents using <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown syntax</a>.</p>

<p>I find myself repeating a lot of the same information, so in order to
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don't_repeat_yourself">DRY</a> up my Markdown files, I create them from several different
components by using template folders. I do it this way because Markdown has no
native way of including sub-documents into a main document.</p>

<ol>
<li>Each template folder contains symlinks to each section Markdown file.</li>
<li>Each symlink is named so that it appears in the right order inside the final document.</li>
</ol>


<p>Here&rsquo;s what the folder structure looks like for my Rails Girls documents:</p>

<pre><code>.
  applicant
    00-intro.md -&gt; ../docs/intro.md
    01-apply.md -&gt; ../docs/applying.md
    99-footer.md -&gt; ../docs/footer.md
    applying.html
    applying.markdown
  coach
    00-intro.md -&gt; ../docs/intro.md
    01-coach.md -&gt; ../docs/coaching-volunteering.md
    99-footer.md -&gt; ../docs/footer.md
    coaching.html
    coaching.markdown
  docs
    applying.md
    coaching-volunteering.md
    footer.md
    intro.md
    sponsor.md
  sponsor
    00-intro.md -&gt; ../docs/intro.md
    02-sponsor.md -&gt; ../docs/sponsor.md
    03-coaching.md -&gt; ../docs/coaching-volunteering.md
    99-footer.md -&gt; ../docs/footer.md
    sponsor.html
    sponsor.markdown
</code></pre>

<p>It&rsquo;s very easy to link the right content inside the template folder. For
example, when I created the <code>coach</code> template folder, I typed in the following
commands:</p>

<pre><code>mkdir coach                                         # Make a template folder and
cd coach/                                           # make it your current working directory
ln -s ../docs/intro.md 00-intro.md                  # Symlink the intro/header
ln -s ../docs/coaching-volunteering.md 01-coach.md  # Symlink the content section(s)
ln -s ../docs/footer.md 99-footer.md                # Symlink the footer/signature
cat *.md                                            # To see how it looks on-screen
cat *.md &gt; coaching.markdown                        # Make a complete markdown document
cat *.md | markdown &gt; coaching.html                 # Generate HTML
</code></pre>

<p>I use <a href="http://markedapp.com/">Marked.app</a> to view Markdown files, so having a complete file is
convenient for me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Talks on Testing (in Ruby)]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/12/three-talks-on-testing/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-12T11:02:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/12/three-talks-on-testing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are three talks on testing in Ruby I think all developers should see. I&rsquo;ve
presented them in the order in which I think they should be watched.</p>

<p>Sandi&rsquo;s and Katrina&rsquo;s talks in particular focus on what testing gives you and
what you should be testing. Andy&rsquo;s talk is a live coding session in which he
TDD&rsquo;s a library.</p>

<ol>
<li>Sandi Metz: <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qPfQM4w4I04">&ldquo;The Magic Tricks of Testing&rdquo;</a> (Ancient City Ruby 2013)</li>
<li>Katrina Owen: <a href="https://vimeo.com/68730418">&ldquo;467 tests, 0 failures, 0 confidence&rdquo;</a> (Railsberry 2013)</li>
<li>Andy Lindeman: <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2aYdtS7FZJA">&ldquo;Building a mocking library&rdquo;</a> (Ancient City Ruby 2013)</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New arrivals on and in Exmouth Market]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/11/new-arrivals-on-and-in-exmouth-market/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-11T08:01:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/11/new-arrivals-on-and-in-exmouth-market</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the last several months, there have been several new arrivals on Exmouth Market.</p>

<p>The latest shop to open up is <strong>Yog</strong>, which sells low-fat frozen yoghurt.
Their prices are quite high (£ 3.20 for a &ldquo;regular&rdquo;), but they are very
refreshing in the recent warm weather and their service is very friendly.</p>

<p>The Japanese restaurant Bincho closed, and in its place is the <strong>Potato Merchant</strong>,
which does American steakhouse-style &ldquo;twice baked&rdquo; potatoes where the potato is
baked, then the starchy insides are mixed with (generally fatty) fillings, put
back inside the skin and crisped up in the oven. I almost avoid stodgy foods at
lunchtime, so I haven&rsquo;t bothered with them.</p>

<p>The premises that had stood empty for months after the Starbucks shut down is
now a <strong>Hummus Brothers</strong>. Ironically, I don&rsquo;t particularly like the hummus
there, but the falafel wraps are very good and about as healthy as a deep-fried
food can be.</p>

<p>And finally, in the market itself there is a new stand (all the way on the Mount
Pleasant end) that sells Brazilian <em>brigadeiros</em>. It&rsquo;s called <strong>The London
Brigadeira</strong>.  <em>Brigadeiros</em> are sweet truffles made of condensed milk and
various flavourings. They are very nice, and quite addictive. You should
definitely stop by and say hello to Emma, the proprietor—there are free
samples, after all!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[London Summertime]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/09/london-summertime/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-09T22:15:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/09/london-summertime</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been really sunny and warm in London for a few days now. At work, we spend
as much time as possible outdoors, which isn&rsquo;t very much time at all—the life
of a software developer may have its perks, but being close to nature isn&rsquo;t
one of them. But the &ldquo;downstairs&rdquo; conference room is getting good use, and
nearby Spa Fields has become our lunch room—ours and everyone else&rsquo;s within a
half-mile.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7432/9249280543_1a8711d675_h.jpg" alt="The Bambinos in Spa Fields" /></p>

<p>We had a sunny spell about a month ago, at the beginning of June, and Spa
Fields were lush with green grass. Now the dryness of summer has baked the
foliage until crisp and brown, but after eight months of cold, rainy grey we
are grateful for the sunshine, regardless.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rails Girls South Florida]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/07/rails-girls-south-florida/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-07T23:26:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/07/rails-girls-south-florida</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been so busy working on the nuts and bolts of organization that I&rsquo;ve
hardly spared a breath to write about what I&rsquo;ve been up to. Exactly <em>what</em> I&rsquo;m
organizing is <a href="http://railsgirls-sfl.org">Rails Girls South Florida</a>, which
will take place in the Miami area in November. It will be awesome!</p>

<p><a href="http://railsgirls-sfl.org"><img src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5506/9232564805_470bb53bbe_o.png" alt="Rails Girls SFL website" /></a></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Rails Girls</h2>

<p><a href="http://railsgirls.com">Rails Girls</a>, in case you don&rsquo;t already know, is a
workshop designed to teach women how to program. The goal is to provide women
with the chance to get excited about technology, especially software
development, and give them the tools they need to build their own ideas.</p>

<p>My own motivation for organizing Rails Girls is to fight the tendency the
software development community has towards building a tall, narrow monoculture and
increase the breadth and diversity of the community by bringing in people from
the outside who are different in important ways.  The community, and therefore
the profession, of software development becomes stronger when many different
people of many different backgrounds take part in it. Gender diversity is
one of the easiest, and most obvious areas in which we can improve our profession
as a whole.</p>

<h2>Workshop at RubyConf 2013 in Miami Beach</h2>

<p>I had the idea to do a Rails Girls workshop just as soon as I saw that
<a href="http://rubyconf.org">RubyConf</a> is taking place in Miami Beach this year. I&rsquo;ve
been an organizer for Rails Girls London since the beginning (a story for
another post), so I&rsquo;m pretty sure I know how to make one happen—it&rsquo;s really not
that complicated, but it does require a fair amount of work and some good
organization. I guess that&rsquo;s why they call it &ldquo;organizing&rdquo;.</p>

<p>I then got on the Rails Girls worldwide team mailing list to see if anyone else
was organizing anything in South Florida, and I checked the website to see if
there had been anything at all in the area. The only thing I found was a
request for a workshop in Fort Lauderdale by &ldquo;Cristina&rdquo;, who sadly forgot to
include her contact information when she made the request. However, I also saw
that newly-minted Ruby Hero <a href="http://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=hone02">Terence Lee</a>
was going to be in South Florida and was interested in helping with the
workshop. I also wrote to Terence to see if he was still interested in helping
organize a workshop—he was.</p>

<p>I then got in touch with Ruby Central, who organize RubyConf, and asked for
their blessing. Abigail Phoenix was tremendously helpful and put me in contact
with the confereence venue to see if we could find some space for the workshop.
She also offered to help promote the workshop via RubyConf&rsquo;s social media.</p>

<p>Our Rails Girls workshop is timed to happen just ahead of RubyConf 2013 so
that we can take advantage of the pool of potential coaches that will flock to
South Florida for the conference. I suspect attendence will be excellent, even
for RubyConf&rsquo;s high standards, thanks in part to the attraction of South
Florida&rsquo;s tropical climate.</p>

<p>Last weekend, I got the web site up and running, but it wasn&rsquo;t pretty, so this
weekend I installed atheme and modified it, making sure the typography is
tolerable. There&rsquo;s still some work to go, but by and large, the site looks
really good.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m using nice fonts from <a href="http://typography.com">typography.com</a>, which my New
Bamboo colleague <a href="http://twitter.com/danbee">Dan Barber</a> turned me on to just
last week. We&rsquo;re both typography lovers.</p>

<p>When the time comes, we&rsquo;ll also get the
<a href="http://github.com/railsgirlslondon/railsgirlslondon">Rails Girls application</a>
up and running. It was written by the organization team of Rails Girls London,
primarily <a href="http://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=despo">Despo Pentara</a>,
and is a very useful tool for putting together events and taking applications.
You can see it in action on the <a href="http://railsgirls.co.uk">Rails Girls London site</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rubyweb]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/06/rubyweb/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-06T11:49:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/06/rubyweb</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/allolex/rubyweb"><strong>Rubyweb</strong></a> is a small program I wrote to
address a small problem, but one that keeps popping up. Apparently, the
&ldquo;normal&rdquo; way of running a simple web server in Ruby is too difficult, so people
have been using Python&rsquo;s <em>SimpleHTTPServer</em> instead. Now I&rsquo;m totally cool with
using Python or any other language&rsquo;s tools to do that, but the main argument
seems to be the number of characters you have to type in order to launch the
web server.</p>

<p><strong>Rubyweb</strong> is very simple to install and use:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>gem install rubyweb
</span><span class='line'>rubyweb</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Have a look at <a href="https://github.com/allolex/rubyweb"><strong>Rubyweb</strong>&rsquo;s GitHub repo</a> and
let me know what you think.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrated blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/06/migrated-blog/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-06T11:46:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/06/migrated-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve migrated my blog to Jekyll/Octopress. The import wasn&rsquo;t perfect, so I&rsquo;ll be adding backin missing images and fixing post bodies that have somehow ended up being titles.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Hardware RAID]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/05/apple-hardware-raid/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/05/apple-hardware-raid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I got home yesterday, I noticed that our 2009 Mac Pro was unresponsive. I
checked to see if it was on the network, and then powered it down. When I
turned it back on, it booted into the recovery volume.</p>

<p>That Mac Pro had a RAID 5 array on it, composed of four 2TB hard drives,
bought for a premium price from Apple so they would support the system.</p>

<p>I opened up the RAID utility and saw that the RAID controller was recognising
all four hard drives were no longer in a RAID set. Although all of them were
reporting that they were &ldquo;ok&rdquo;, the RAID set and therefore the RAID volume were
gone.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I telephoned Apple, happy to pay for someone to guide me through the recovery
since there is <strong>absolutely no</strong> documentation on recovering a RAID 5 system
with a missing RAID set. Their technical support was courteous, but not well-
informed.</p>

<p>After going over it and leaving it with them to &ldquo;investigate&rdquo; further, I
received a phone call today from the person who was helping me. The short of
it is that Apple say if your RAID set is missing, you&rsquo;re screwed. They also
say that you should not be using RAID for backup purposes, as it&rsquo;s only
designed to protect you from disk failure.</p>

<p>But of course it wasn&rsquo;t a disk that failed. It was the RAID itself, and it
took out all our data with it. We will be restoring from backup, but the size
of the RAID (4.7TB) meant that backing up to external drives is complicated,
and our backups are not completely up-to-date.</p>

<p>The point is that we paid nearly £500 for the RAID card and it has proved to
be a complete waste of money. If your Dell RAID dies on you, then Dell will
help you recover it, but clearly Apple don&rsquo;t take their business support
seriously.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This is how we sleep now, apparently.]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/15/this-is-how-we-sleep-now-apparently/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/15/this-is-how-we-sleep-now-apparently</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7414/9223270343_eb87b433bd_o.jpg" alt="Billie" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Peeking out]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/14/peeking-out/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/14/peeking-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2856/9226048798_ee08c1eefb_o.jpg" alt="nose peeking out" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Billie basking in the autumn]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/14/billie-basking-in-the-autumn/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/14/billie-basking-in-the-autumn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8170/8069903576_aa49b29b1e_h.jpg" alt="Billie basking in autumn" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Condensation]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/13/condensation/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/13/condensation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3733/9226050254_82a23cea5e_h.jpg" alt="Condensation" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[London bus arrival]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/12/london-bus-arrival/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/12/london-bus-arrival</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7372/9226050360_083dec6794_o.jpg" alt="bus arrival" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Billie always wants to play bones when we are getting dressed.]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/12/billie-always-wants-to-play-bones-when-we-are-getting-dressed/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/12/billie-always-wants-to-play-bones-when-we-are-getting-dressed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5522/9223272055_38d88e9ac0_o.jpg" alt="Billie with bone" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gentlemen]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/11/ladies-and-gentlemen/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/11/ladies-and-gentlemen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2817/9226050408_4978841901_o.jpg" alt="gentlemen" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bavette with chips at Medcalf]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/08/bavette-with-chips-at-medcalf--view-on-path/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/02/08/bavette-with-chips-at-medcalf&#8211;view-on-path</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://allolex.net/tumblr_files/tumblr_mhwo0mmWz21r95zg4o1_1280.jpg" alt="Bavette at Medcalf" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overheard: Old version of the internet]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/01/31/old-version-internet/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/01/31/old-version-internet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>OH: &ldquo;they&rsquo;ve got an old version of the Internet on&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ana of Lisbon]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/01/30/ana-de-lisboa/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/01/30/ana-de-lisboa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8096/8420784501_77607efe66_h.jpg" alt="Ana of Lisbon" /></p>

<p>Ana in Lisbon, 2009.</p>

<p>Mine from a few years back</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
