<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: live | Allolexicon]]></title>
  <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/categories/live/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://allolex.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-09T19:38:37+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://allolex.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Damon Davison]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fugazi Live Series: Los Angeles, CA USA 9/08/91]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2012/01/04/fugazi-live-series-los-angeles-ca-usa-90891/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2012/01/04/fugazi-live-series-los-angeles-ca-usa-90891</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://assets.dischord.com/images.d/photo/image/588/FLS%0A0395_flyer_1.jpg" alt="Palladium gig flyer" /></p>

<p>Dischord have started their release of the Fugazi Live Series.</p>

<blockquote><p>Between 1987 and 2003, Fugazi played over 1000 concerts in all 50 states and
all over the world. Over 800 of these shows were recorded by the band&rsquo;s sound
engineers. The goal of this project is to make each of these recordings
available to download for a small fee. We will start with 130 shows and
release more monthly until we&rsquo;re done. A searchable archive lists each show
along with available photos, flyers and general show info. Each listing with a
download offers a streaming preview of material for sound quality as well as
the reading and posting of comments on the show and the recording.</p>

<p>The size and scope this archive dictates that it will remain a semi-
permanent work-in-progress. We welcome visitors to contribute photos,
recordings, corrections, and any additional info that may be missing from
specific shows. Please see the About section for information about
contributing content.</p></blockquote>

<p>I was at the <a href="http://www.dischord.com/fugazi_live_series/los-angeles-ca-usa-90891">September 8th show at the Hollywood Palladium in
1991</a>,
but I don&rsquo;t have a contiguous memory of the gig. Hearing the audio from the
show when it is released is certain to bring back some memories.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m afraid neither of the opening bands left much of an impression, but then
again we were there for Fugazi. It was a big deal.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
