<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: community | Allolexicon]]></title>
  <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/categories/community/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://allolex.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-13T12:20:02+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://allolex.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Damon Davison]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rails Girls South Florida]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/07/rails-girls-south-florida/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-07T23:26:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/07/rails-girls-south-florida</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been so busy working on the nuts and bolts of organization that I&rsquo;ve
hardly spared a breath to write about what I&rsquo;ve been up to. Exactly <em>what</em> I&rsquo;m
organizing is <a href="http://railsgirls-sfl.org">Rails Girls South Florida</a>, which
will take place in the Miami area in November. It will be awesome!</p>

<p><a href="http://railsgirls-sfl.org"><img src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5506/9232564805_470bb53bbe_o.png" alt="Rails Girls SFL website" /></a></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Rails Girls</h2>

<p><a href="http://railsgirls.com">Rails Girls</a>, in case you don&rsquo;t already know, is a
workshop designed to teach women how to program. The goal is to provide women
with the chance to get excited about technology, especially software
development, and give them the tools they need to build their own ideas.</p>

<p>My own motivation for organizing Rails Girls is to fight the tendency the
software development community has towards building a tall, narrow monoculture and
increase the breadth and diversity of the community by bringing in people from
the outside who are different in important ways.  The community, and therefore
the profession, of software development becomes stronger when many different
people of many different backgrounds take part in it. Gender diversity is
one of the easiest, and most obvious areas in which we can improve our profession
as a whole.</p>

<h2>Workshop at RubyConf 2013 in Miami Beach</h2>

<p>I had the idea to do a Rails Girls workshop just as soon as I saw that
<a href="http://rubyconf.org">RubyConf</a> is taking place in Miami Beach this year. I&rsquo;ve
been an organizer for Rails Girls London since the beginning (a story for
another post), so I&rsquo;m pretty sure I know how to make one happen—it&rsquo;s really not
that complicated, but it does require a fair amount of work and some good
organization. I guess that&rsquo;s why they call it &ldquo;organizing&rdquo;.</p>

<p>I then got on the Rails Girls worldwide team mailing list to see if anyone else
was organizing anything in South Florida, and I checked the website to see if
there had been anything at all in the area. The only thing I found was a
request for a workshop in Fort Lauderdale by &ldquo;Cristina&rdquo;, who sadly forgot to
include her contact information when she made the request. However, I also saw
that newly-minted Ruby Hero <a href="http://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=hone02">Terence Lee</a>
was going to be in South Florida and was interested in helping with the
workshop. I also wrote to Terence to see if he was still interested in helping
organize a workshop—he was.</p>

<p>I then got in touch with Ruby Central, who organize RubyConf, and asked for
their blessing. Abigail Phoenix was tremendously helpful and put me in contact
with the confereence venue to see if we could find some space for the workshop.
She also offered to help promote the workshop via RubyConf&rsquo;s social media.</p>

<p>Our Rails Girls workshop is timed to happen just ahead of RubyConf 2013 so
that we can take advantage of the pool of potential coaches that will flock to
South Florida for the conference. I suspect attendence will be excellent, even
for RubyConf&rsquo;s high standards, thanks in part to the attraction of South
Florida&rsquo;s tropical climate.</p>

<p>Last weekend, I got the web site up and running, but it wasn&rsquo;t pretty, so this
weekend I installed atheme and modified it, making sure the typography is
tolerable. There&rsquo;s still some work to go, but by and large, the site looks
really good.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m using nice fonts from <a href="http://typography.com">typography.com</a>, which my New
Bamboo colleague <a href="http://twitter.com/danbee">Dan Barber</a> turned me on to just
last week. We&rsquo;re both typography lovers.</p>

<p>When the time comes, we&rsquo;ll also get the
<a href="http://github.com/railsgirlslondon/railsgirlslondon">Rails Girls application</a>
up and running. It was written by the organization team of Rails Girls London,
primarily <a href="http://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=despo">Despo Pentara</a>,
and is a very useful tool for putting together events and taking applications.
You can see it in action on the <a href="http://railsgirls.co.uk">Rails Girls London site</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
