<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: market | Allolexicon]]></title>
  <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/categories/market/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://allolex.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-12T20:56:11+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://allolex.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Damon Davison]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New arrivals on and in Exmouth Market]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/11/new-arrivals-on-and-in-exmouth-market/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-11T08:01:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2013/07/11/new-arrivals-on-and-in-exmouth-market</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the last several months, there have been several new arrivals on Exmouth Market.</p>

<p>The latest shop to open up is <strong>Yog</strong>, which sells low-fat frozen yoghurt.
Their prices are quite high (£ 3.20 for a &ldquo;regular&rdquo;), but they are very
refreshing in the recent warm weather and their service is very friendly.</p>

<p>The Japanese restaurant Bincho closed, and in its place is the <strong>Potato Merchant</strong>,
which does American steakhouse-style &ldquo;twice baked&rdquo; potatoes where the potato is
baked, then the starchy insides are mixed with (generally fatty) fillings, put
back inside the skin and crisped up in the oven. I almost avoid stodgy foods at
lunchtime, so I haven&rsquo;t bothered with them.</p>

<p>The premises that had stood empty for months after the Starbucks shut down is
now a <strong>Hummus Brothers</strong>. Ironically, I don&rsquo;t particularly like the hummus
there, but the falafel wraps are very good and about as healthy as a deep-fried
food can be.</p>

<p>And finally, in the market itself there is a new stand (all the way on the Mount
Pleasant end) that sells Brazilian <em>brigadeiros</em>. It&rsquo;s called <strong>The London
Brigadeira</strong>.  <em>Brigadeiros</em> are sweet truffles made of condensed milk and
various flavourings. They are very nice, and quite addictive. You should
definitely stop by and say hello to Emma, the proprietor—there are free
samples, after all!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
