<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: pods cms framework | Allolexicon]]></title>
  <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/categories/pods-cms-framework/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://allolex.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-12T20:56:11+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://allolex.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Damon Davison]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Pods CMS Framework for Wordpress]]></title>
    <link href="http://allolex.net/blog/2011/12/28/the-pods-cms-framework-for-wordpress/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://allolex.net/blog/2011/12/28/the-pods-cms-framework-for-wordpress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://podscms.org/">The Pods CMS Framework for Wordpress</a></p>

<p>We decided on WordPress about a year ago. We&rsquo;d had some disastrous development
done on Drupal prior to that&mdash;a completely failed undertaking which took a
good chunk out of our budget for further development, and after we finished
picking up the rubble, it became clear to us that working with our existing
CMS was the way to go. No offense to Drupal, of course.</p>

<p>WordPress used to be just WordPress, a pretty good blog written in PHP like
Drupal, which isn&rsquo;t exactly my favourite language on Earth. Over the last few
years, some developers have really taken advantage of WP&rsquo;s plugin and modular
architecture and have created some plugins that completely transform your WP
installation. The Pods CMS framework is one such plugin.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s not much Pods does that you can&rsquo;t do with custom content types and
custom coding. Okay, there&rsquo;s not anything it can do that can&rsquo;t be done with
custom coding, but what Pods does is provide a framework upon which you can
build content types for your site, the &ldquo;pods&rdquo;. As someone who has done it the
other way, I can say Pods is a much easier path to take and you get a lot of
stuff &ldquo;for free&rdquo; along with it, including a relatively useful MVC-esque
structure to put everything into and access to code &ldquo;helpers&rdquo; that allow you
do implement special features, for example resizing images on upload.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
